MANI NAIK

+91(986) 730-6334 \diamond Bengaluru, IN

maninaik111@gmail.com ♦ linkedin ♦ maninaik.github.io ♦ github ♦ leetcode

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 3+ years of experience as a front end developer. Currently working at DataPOEM. Crafting diverse user interfaces leveraging NextJS and React. Worked on login, authentication screens as well as dashboards tailored for analytics clients. Solved 250+ Questions on LeetCode.

SKILLS

Languages JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Python.

Technologies React, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, React Query, Yarn, Webpack, Git, Postman.

EXPERIENCE

Front-end Developer

July 2023 - Present Bengaluru, IN

DATAPOEM

- Implemented changes to the webpack and nginx configurations resulting in a Lighthouse performance metric improvement from 54 to 72 (33%) for an existing Vue app.
- I streamlined authentication for our internal tools web app by using Next-Auth. Successfully integrated Azure-AD login functionality into Vue App, leveraging the MSAL library reducing the authentication related tickets by 90%.
- I spearheaded the creation of a comprehensive UI library using shaden/ui within a Nx Monorepo. My focus on accessibility was central to this project, ensuring usability for all.
- Resolving bugs and introducing new functionalities to an existing Vue2-based web app.

Application Development Analyst ACCENTURE

Jan 2021 - July 2023

 $Mumbai,\ IN$

- Developed and maintained a high-traffic search tool, significantly improving user experience and efficiency for thousands of daily users, boosting platform engagement.
- Optimized dashboard code and introduced widgets, slashing load times by 23% and significantly boosting overall performance.
- Collaborated with the client's design team to convert wireframes into efficient and accessible user interfaces, significantly improving user experience, satisfaction, and project success.
- Created a React starter kit that expedited Accenture client onboarding, reducing setup time and boosting time-to-market and client satisfaction.
- Maintained and updated various website sections using React, AngularJS, Javascript and Sass, significantly enhancing user experience with a consistent, polished interface, leading to a 20% increase in user engagement.

PROJECTS

Nextflix - Netflix clone: A web app using NextJS, ReactJS and Hasura GraphQL. It uses the youtube API to show the videos. (Try it here) (github)

Library Management System using NodeJS: A web app using NodeJS, Pug and MongoDB. It can be used by the librarian to track books, genres and their authors. (github)

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology. Atharva College of Engineering August 2016 - October 2020